Nora England Papers
Nettie Lee Benson Latin American Collection
- Series IV: Teaching and Academic Research Materials
  - Subseries: PLFM
    - Descripcion General del Proyecto Linguistico Francisco Marroquin, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - PLFM Correspondence, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Subsubseries: PLFM Surveys, 1971
      - Cuestionario Linguistico, Dialectales en las Lenguas de Guatemala, Mam, 1970-1971 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      - Cuestionario Linguistico, Dialectales en las Lenguas de Guatemala, Teco, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      - Cuestionario Linguistico, Dialectales en las Lenguas de Guatemala, Aguacatec, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      - Cuestionario Linguistico, Dialectales en las Lenguas de Guatemala, Chortí, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 14)
      - Cuestionario Linguistico, Dialectales en las Lenguas de Guatemala, Kanjobal, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 15)
      - Cuestionario Linguistico, Dialectales en las Lenguas de Guatemala, Kekchi Pocomam, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 16)
      - Cuestionario Linguistico, Dialectales en las Lenguas de Guatemala, K'iche' de Santa Catarina, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 17)
      - Cuestionario Linguistico, Dialectales en las Lenguas de Guatemala, Mam, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 18)
      - Cuestionario Linguistico, Dialectales en las Lenguas de Guatemala, Mam de Ixtahuacán, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 19)
      - Cuestionario Linguistico, Dialectales en las Lenguas de Guatemala, Mopan, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 20)
      - Cuestionario Linguistico, Dialectales en las Lenguas de Guatemala, Quiché, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 21)
      - Cuestionario Linguistico, Dialectales en las Lenguas de Guatemala, Tzutujil, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 22)
      - Cuestionario Linguistico Para la Investigacion de las Variaciones Dialectales en las Lenguas de Guatemala, blank survey, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 23)
      - Las Lenguas de Guatemala, Ordenadas Segun su Clasificacion Genetica y Distribucion Geografica con sus Dialetos Indicados y Tambien los Pueblos Donde se Hablan y los Numeros de Hablantes (Censo de 1964), 1973 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Subsubseries: PLFM Field Work and Analysis (Box 12)
      - PLFM Word Lists, 1970-1971 (Box 12, Folder 25)
      - PLFM Workbook Binder, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 26)
      - Guatemala Maps and Pamphlets, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 27)
      - Orthographies, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 28)
      - Mayan Language Groups, 1971 (Box 12, Folder 29)
      - PLFM Workbook Binder, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 30)
      - PLFM Workbook Binder, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 31)
      - PLFM Workbook Binder, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 32)
      - Alfabeto Ilustrado, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 33)
      - Other Mayan Language Materials, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 34)
      - Linguistic Vocab, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 35)
      - Mayan Dictionary PLFM, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 36)
      - Cakchiquel, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 37)
      - Swadesh List, undated (Box 12, Folder 38)
      - Sipacapa, undated (Box 12, Folder 39)
      - Carchá, undated (Box 12, Folder 40)
      - Atitlán, undated (Box 12, Folder 41)
      - Cakchiquel, undated (Box 12, Folder 42)
      - Comalapa, undated (Box 12, Folder 43)
      - Languages by Town, PLFM, undated (Box 12, Folder 44)
      - Alfabetos, PLFM, undated (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - Subsubseries: PLFM Courses and Course Material
      - PLFM Workbook, Grasp of Morphology Course, Binder, 1972 (Box 12, Folder 46)
      - Summer Course, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 47)
      - Mayan Cartillas, 1977 (Box 12, Folder 48)
      - Taller PLFM, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 49)
      - PLFM, Programa de Clausura del Curso Linguistico, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 50)
      - Curso IV, Syntax, undated (Box 12, Folder 51)
      - Kaufman, Terrence, Las Lenguas Indigenas de Guatemala: Alfabetos y Ortografias Propuestos Para Cada Lengua Indigena de Guatemala, Volumen II, 1973 March (Box 12, Folder 52)
      - Kaufman, Terrence, Principios Ortograficos Para Escribir Las Lenguas Mayances, Volumen I, 1973 December (Box 12, Folder 53)
      - Análisis de Datos y Guía de Preparación, Diccionarios Indígenas, Parte I, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 54)
      - Análisis de Datos y Guía de Preparación, Diccionarios Indígenas, Parte II, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      - Kaufman, Terrence, Proyecto de Alfabetos y Ortografias Para Escribir Las Lenguas Mayances, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Subseries IV: Mississippi State University
    - Subsubseries: Choctaw Course Material
      - Grammar of the Choctaw Language, 1970 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      - Chanta Anompa, An Introduction to the Choctaw Language, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      - Suppletive Verbs in Choctaw, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 5)
      - Choctaw Orthography, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 6)
      - Choctaw Newsletters, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 7)
      - Choctaw Notes, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 8)
      - Choctaw Articles in Discourse, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 9)
      - Choctaw Lesson Planning, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 10)
      - Choctaw Word Lists, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
      - Choctaw Sentence Structure, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
      - Southeastern State Choctaw Course, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
      - Choctaw Stories, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
      - Choctaw Numbers, undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
      - Choctaw Christmas Traditions, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
      - Heath, Jeffrey, Syntactic Cases, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
      - Choctaw Kin Terms, undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
      - Choctaw Student Sheets, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
      - Choctaw Teaching Materials, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
      - Choctaw Student Materials, undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
      - Rule Variants in Choctaw, undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
      - Introduction to Choctaw Math Curriculum, undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Subsubseries: Other Course Material
      - Cree Course Materials, 1968-1971 (Box 13, Folder 24)
      - Mesquakie Course Materials, 1919-1978 (Box 13, Folder 25)
      - Seminole Materials, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 26)
      - Mikasuki Phonology, 1962 (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Subsubseries: Bilingual Education for Choctaws of Mississippi (BECOM)/Bilingual Education
      - BECOM Overview, undated (Box 13, Folder 28)
      - Mississippi State University, Bilingual Education Bibliography, undated (Box 13, Folder 29)
      - BECOM Haas Muskogean, undated (Box 13, Folder 30)
      - BECOM Verb List, undated (Box 13, Folder 31)
      - BECOM Child Literacy, undated (Box 13, Folder 32)
      - BECOM Bulletin Board Ideas, undated (Box 13, Folder 33)
      - Bill Pulle Comments on Bilingual Education, undated (Box 13, Folder 34)
      - BECOM Conference Program, undated (Box 13, Folder 35)
      - Bilingual Education Misc. Materials, 1972-1975 (Box 13, Folder 36)
      - Mississippi Curriculum Development, 1974-1975 (Box 13, Folder 37)
      - BECOM Adult Literacy, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 38)
      - BECOM Cahtat Nihak Hollo Cito Nana Oklittima, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 39)
      - BECOM Dictionary, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 40)
      - Ante Proyecto de Programa de Educacion Primaria Bilingue en Guatemala, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 41)
      - BECOM Mailing List, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 42)
      - BECOM Report to Tribal Council, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 43)
      - BECOM Beginners Dictionary, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 44)
      - BECOM Curriculum Outline, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 45)
      - BECOM Curriculum Proposal, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 46)
      - Sokhata Anopa, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 47)
      - Oklosiat Nita Afama, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 48)
      - Nawaho Alla, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 49)
      - Nitayat Ofosik Ilawilih, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 50)
      - Nita Homakbi Cito, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 51)
      - Loksi Nika Issi Ittipakha, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 52)
      - Hattak Nana Ist Ilawata (The Boastful Man), 1976 (Box 13, Folder 53)
      - Hoski Ist Anopa, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 54)
      - Cofkiat Nahokopa Ikhana, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 55)
      - Sokka Anopa, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 56)
      - Anopa Osi, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 57)
      - Bilingual Education Project, Mam Final Exam, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 58)
      - Headstart Books, undated (Box 13, Folder 59)
      - Canta Imanopa Tokio Atoksali, undated (Box 13, Folder 60)
      - Sokkasi Toccina, undated (Box 13, Folder 61)
  - Subseries V: University of Iowa
    - Kusaal Teaching Material, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 65)
    - Dialetologia Mam, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 66)
    - Mam Dictionary Presentation, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 67)
    - Escritura Jeroglifica Maya, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 68)
    - Cleveland Conference on Mayan Text and Discourse, 1987 October (Box 13, Folder 69)
    - Course Materials, The Structure of Mayan Languages, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Language Communities, States, and Global Culture: The Discource of Identity in the Americas, Conference at the University of Iowa, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Subseries VI: Academia de las Lenguas Mayas de Guatemala (ALMG)
    - ALMG Constitution, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - El Pasivo Mam, Taller Maya IV, Palenque, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Talleres Mayas, El Pasivo, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Taller on Mayan Language V, Guatemala City, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Taller on Mayan Language VIII, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Taller, Academia de las Lenguas Mayas, 1987 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Taller Maya, 1989 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Taller Maya, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Taller Maya, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Taller Maya, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Subseries VII: Oklajuuj Keej Maya' Ajtz'iib' (OKMA)
    - Subsubseries: OKMA Course Materials
      - 1992 y el discurso de encubrimiento (Box 14, Folder 13)
      - Complementación, OKMA, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 14)
      - El Enfoque Agentivo en Q'anjob'al, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 15)
      - OKMA articulos, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 16)
      - OKMA presentaciones, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 17)
      - OKMA Gramática Pedagógica Mam, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 18)
      - Los Idiomas Mayas y los Acuerdos de Paz en Guatemala, Waykan, 1999 March (Box 14, Folder 19)
      - Las Vocales en K'ichee', 2000 August (Box 14, Folder 20)
      - OKMA, Topic and Focus, 2002 (Box 14, Folder 21)
      - OKMA, Textos, undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
      - OKMA Formulario de Control de Digitalización y Archivado de Materiales, undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
      - OKMA Formulario de Control, Idioma Achi, undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
      - OKMA Formulario de Control, Idioma Akateko, undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
      - OKMA Formulario de Control, Idioma Kaqchikel, undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
      - OKMA Formulario de Control, Idioma Poqomchi', undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
      - OKMA Formulario de Control, Idioma Q'eqchi', undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
      - OKMA Formulario de Control, Idioma Quiche, undated (Box 14, Folder 29)
      - OKMA Formulario de Control, Idioma Tz'utoji', undated (Box 14, Folder 30)
      - OKMA, Articulos Varios, undated (Box 14, Folder 31)
      - Sustantivos Verbales, Cláusulas? K'ichee', undated (Box 14, Folder 32)
    - Subsubseries: OKMA Projects
      - Diccionario Compartativo de los Idiomas Mayas Proposal, 1990-1995 (Box 14, Folder 33)
        This folder contains some restricted materials.
      - Capacitación Tecnico-Lingüístico e Investigación Dialectal Proposal, 1997-1998 (Box 14, Folder 34)
      - Elaboración de Materiales Didácticos y Técnicos, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 35)
      - OKMA/CIRMA Project Proposal, 1998-1999 (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Subsubseries: OKMA Projects: Documentation of Two Mayan Languages
      - OKMA, Endangered Languages Documentation Program (ELDP) Project Award for the Documentation of Two Mayan Lanuages in Guatemala: Uspanteko and Sakapulteko, 2002-2003 (Box 14, Folder 38)
      - Documentation of Two Mayan Languages: Uspanteko and Sakapulteko, ELDP Annual Report, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 39)
      - Documentation of Two Mayan Languages of Guatemala Uspanteko and Sakapulteko, Project Materials, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 40)
      - Documentation of Two Mayan Languages: Uspanteko and Sakapulteko, Shoebox, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 41)
      - Documentation of Two Mayan Languages: Uspanteko and Sakapulteko, ELDP End of Award Report, 2003-2006 (Box 14, Folder 42)
      - ELDP Application for Documentation of Two Mayan Languages: Uspanteko and Sakapulteko, 2003-2006 (Box 14, Folder 43)
      - Documentation of Two Mayan Languages: Uspanteko and Sakapulteko, Documentation, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 44)
      - Documentation of Two Mayan Languages: Uspanteko and Sakapulteko, ELDP Annual Report, 2004 (Box 14, Folder 45)
      - Documentation of Two Mayan Languages: Uspanteko and Sakapulteko, Progress Report, 2004-2005 (Box 14, Folder 46)
      - Documentation of Two Mayan Languages: Uspanteko and Sakapulteko, Guide to Using Shoebox, 2005 (Box 14, Folder 47)
    - Subsubseries: OKMA Projects: Documentación de Awakateko y Teko, Diccionarios de Mam y Kaqchikel
      - Documentación de Awakateko y Teko, Diccionarios de Mam y Kaqchikel, Project Materials, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 48)
      - Documentación de Awakateko y Teko, Diccionarios de Mam y Kaqchikel, Project Proposa, 2003-2006 (Box 14, Folder 49)
      - Documentación de Awakateko y Teko, Diccionarios de Mam y Kaqchikel, Project Documentation, 2003-2004 (Box 14, Folder 50)
      - OKMA Grant from the Norwegian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 51)
    - Subsubseries: OKMA Administrative
      - Course Evaluation Guide, 1992-1993 (Box 14, Folder 52)
      - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      - Meeting Minutes, 1999-2001 (Box 15, Folder 2)
      - Meeting Minutes, 1999-2001 (Box 15, Folder 3)
      - Financial Report, 2003-2004 (Box 15, Folder 4)
      - Financial Statement Report, 2003-2004 (Box 15, Folder 5)
      - Oxlajuuj Keej Maya' Ajtz'iib' (OKMA), Quienes Somos, circa 2000s (Box 15, Folder 6)
      - OKMA Conference, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Subseries VIII: University of Texas at Austin
    - AILLA Project Proposal, 1999-2000 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - List of Mayan Language Courses at U.S Universities, 2001 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Where Mam Departs from the Fold, Agents and Intransitivity, Handout, 2016 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - K'ichee Course Materials, LLILAS, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Supplemental Endowment Plan for LLILAS, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Gramatica Mam, undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Subsubseries: Conferences
      - La Lingüística Al Servicio de los Idiomas Indígenas, 2002 (Box 15, Folder 14)
      - Apoyando Literaturas Indígenas de Latinoamérica, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 15)
      - Congreso de Idiomas Indígenas de Latinoamérica I, 2003 (Box 15, Folder 16)
      - Congreso de Idiomas Indígenas de Latinoamérica II, 2005 (Box 15, Folder 17)
      - Congreso de Idiomas Indígenas de Latinoamérica III, 2007 (Box 15, Folder 18)
      - Congreso de Idiomas Indígenas de Latinoamérica IV-1, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 19)
      - Congreso de Idiomas Indígenas de Latinoamérica IV-2, 2009 (Box 15, Folder 20)
      - Congreso de Idiomas Indígenas de Latinoamérica V-1, 2011 (Box 15, Folder 21)
      - Congreso de Idiomas Indígenas de Latinoamérica V-2, 2011 (Box 15, Folder 22)
      - Congreso de Idiomas Indígenas de Latinoamérica VI, 2013 (Box 15, Folder 23)
      - Congreso de Idiomas Indígenas de Latinoamérica VII, 2015 (Box 15, Folder 24)
      - Congreso de Idiomas Indígenas de Latinoamérica VIII, 2017 (Box 15, Folder 25)
      - Congreso de Idiomas Indígenas de Latinoamérica IX, 2019 (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Subseries: Miscellaneous Teaching Materials
    - Ethnosemantics, undated (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Marking, undated (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Language Acquisition References, undated (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Mayan Overview, undated (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Language Change, undated (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Social Stratification of Speech, undated (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Ethnography of Speaking, undated (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Elaborated and Refuted Codes, undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Native American Bilingual Education, undated (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Bilingualism: The Americas, undated (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Overlay for Berlin and Kay, undated (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Problem Sets- Originals, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Anthropological Linguistics, Fall 1979 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Anthropological Linguistics, Spring 1978 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Script- Phonetics Tape, Linguistics Department, undated (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Phonology Exercises, undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Tag Questions, undated (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Language Planning, 1978 December 6 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Tojolab'al Handout, undated (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Language and Culture, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Mam Grammatical Overview, Spring 1980 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Language and Culture, Fall 1978 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Language and Culture, Fall 1977 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Language and Culture, Spring 1988 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Language and Culture, Spring 1982 (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Paper: Language and Culture Ideas, undated (Box 22, Folder 26)
    - Linguistic Features of Verbal and Non-Verbal Communication, undated (Box 22, Folder 27)
    - Syntax, undated (Box 22, Folder 28)
    - Morphological Processes, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 29)
    - Proxemics and Kinesics, 1978 October 25 (Box 22, Folder 30)
    - Language and Culture, Phonology, undated (Box 22, Folder 31)
    - Lexical Codes and Subcultures, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 32)
    - Lecture on the History of Linguistics, Indiana University Press, 1967 (Box 22, Folder 33)
    - Language and Culture Class Materials on Boas and Sapir, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 34)
    - Notes on Levi-Strauss, undated (Box 22, Folder 35)
    - Emics and Etics, undated (Box 22, Folder 36)
    - Whorf, Language and Mind, undated (Box 22, Folder 37)
    - Componential Analysis and Kinship, undated (Box 22, Folder 38)
    - Ethnology of Mesoamerica syllabi and course materials, circa 1980s (Box 22, Folder 39)
    - Ethnology of Mesoamerica course materials, Fall 1987 (Box 22, Folder 40)
    - Various Materials on Mesoamerica, undated (Box 22, Folder 41)
    - Course Syllabi of Other Professors at the University of Iowa, 1977-1985 (Box 22, Folder 42)
    - Koutsoudas- proseminar, Fall 1976 (Box 22, Folder 43)
    - Ringan- Phonology Exercises, undated (Box 22, Folder 44)
    - Martin, Laura Courses, 1977-1986 (Box 22, Folder 45)
    - Lecture, Bilingual Education, undated (Box 22, Folder 46)
    - Language in Linguistic Anthropology, undated (Box 22, Folder 47)
    - Lecture- Anthropology + Linguistics, undated (Box 22, Folder 48)
    - Mam Ergavtivity Talk, 1982 February (Box 22, Folder 49)
    - Lecture- Language and Culture, Mayan, undated (Box 22, Folder 50)
    - Lecture- Language and Culture, Mayan, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 51)
    - Field Analysis materials for a course in Anthropological Linguistics, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 52)
    - Swadesh word list, undated (Box 22, Folder 53)
    - Phonetic symbols, undated (Box 22, Folder 54)
    - Mam morphology, undated (Box 22, Folder 55)
    - Mam Ergativity, undated (Box 22, Folder 56)
    - Navajo Syntax and Semantics, undated (Box 22, Folder 57)
    - Pragmatics Mam Text, undated (Box 22, Folder 58)
    - Mayan Indians and the Crisis in Guatemala, Revolution, Reaction, and Reform in Central America Conference, 1983 April (Box 22, Folder 59)
    - Lecture- Languages of Mesoamerica, undated (Box 22, Folder 60)
    - Syntax Seminar, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 61)
    - Mam Seminar, 1980 (Box 22, Folder 62)
    - Lecture- Language Contact, Pidgins, undated (Box 22, Folder 63)
    - EDF 3323 Intro to Bilingual-Bicultural Education, Fall 1976 (Box 22, Folder 64)
    - Others, course materials, 1977-1979 (Box 22, Folder 65)
    - APY 310, Intro to General Anthropological Linguistics course materials, Fall 1970 (Box 22, Folder 66)
    - APY 503, Intro to Field Methods- Hardman, Spring 1971 (Box 22, Folder 67)
    - G. Miller- Linguistics Exam, undated (Box 22, Folder 68)
    - APY 311 Phonology Course- Hardman, Winter 1971 (Box 22, Folder 69)
    - Introductory Linguistics, undated (Box 22, Folder 70)
    - Ethnosemantics, undated (Box 22, Folder 71)
    - Problem sets, undated (Box 22, Folder 72)
    - American phonetic alphabet, undated (Box 22, Folder 73)
    - Phonemic exercises, undated (Box 22, Folder 74)
    - Problem set- Phonemics, Kaqchikel, undated (Box 22, Folder 75)
    - Distinctive features, undated (Box 22, Folder 76)
    - Problem set- Phonological Rules, undated (Box 22, Folder 77)
    - Morphological Processes and Exercises, undated (Box 22, Folder 78)
    - Problem set- Swahili Morphology, undated (Box 22, Folder 79)
    - Problem set- Turkish Morphology, undated (Box 22, Folder 80)
    - Syntax- Word Order, undated (Box 22, Folder 81)
    - Problem set- syntactic function, undated (Box 22, Folder 82)
    - Problem set- Phrase Structures, undated (Box 22, Folder 83)
    - Syntax- Phrase Structure Rules, undated (Box 22, Folder 84)
    - Problem set- Transformations, undated (Box 22, Folder 85)
    - Variation in a Mayan Language: Implications for Literacy and correspondence, circa 1980s (Box 22, Folder 86)
    - Mayan Metaphor and Artistic Expression, 1988 November 10 (Box 22, Folder 87)
    - Guatemalan Politics and A Conference Schedule on the Guatemalan Tragedy, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 88)
    - Mayan Languages Map, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 89)
    - Mayan Languages and Linguistics, miscellaneous materials, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 90)
    - Cultural anthropology- English class, undated (Box 22, Folder 91)
    - England, Nora C., "Ergativity in Mamean (Mayan) Languages" and Mam Ergativity handout, circa 1980s (Box 22, Folder 92)
    - Mayan Languages and Linguistics- Academic Seminar, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 93)
    - Mayan Languages, Santa Barbara talk, 1985 March (Box 22, Folder 94)
- Series V: Fieldwork and Analysis
  - Subseries I: Field Notebooks
    - Ixtahuacán - Mam - Book II, 1972 October-November (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Ixtahuacán - Mam - Book III, 1972 November-December (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Ixtahuacán - Mam - Book IV, 1972 December-1973 July (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Ixtahuacán - Mam - Book V, 1973 June-September (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Ixtahuacán - Mam - Book VI, 1973 September-October (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Ixtahuacán - Mam - Book 7, 1974 July (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Ixtahuacán - Mam - Book 8, 1974 July (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Ixtahuacán - Mam - Book 9, 1974 July (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Ixtahuacán - Mam - Book 10, 1974 July (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - Ixtahuacán - Mam - Book 11, 1974 August-November (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - Ixtahuacán - Mam - Book 12, 1979 June-July (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Ixtahuacán - Mam - #13, Summer 1980 (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - Mam I 85-1, Book 14, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - Mam I 85-2, Book 15, 1985 (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - Index - Mam - San Ildefonso Ixtahuacán, undated (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Teco - Book 1, 1984 February-March 5 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Teco - Book 2, 1984 March 6-May 14 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Teco - Book 3, 1984 April-May 1 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Teco - Book 4, 1984 May 1-5 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Teco - Book 5, 1984 May 5-15 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Teco - Book 6, 1984 May 16 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Teco - Book 7, 1984 June 6-26 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Teco - Book 8, 1984 July 26 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Index Teco, 1984 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - San Juan Ostumcalco - Mam - Book 1 - PLFM, 1973 May 1-June 6 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - San Ildefonso Ixtahuacán - Verbs - PLFM, 1973 April 26-May 29 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - San Juan Ostumcalco - Mam - Verbs - PLFM, 1973 April 30-May 4 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Tapachula #5 San Cristobal de las Casas, 1984 January 22-June 27 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Mam O 85-1, 1985 July 8-July 9 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Mam O 85-2, 1985 July 9-August 2 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Tactiteco 85-1, 1985 August 15-August 19 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Tactiteco 85-2, 1985 August 22-August 25 (Box 16, Folder 18)